So now we've gone through
all of our integration processes
and we're at the end with
closed project or phase.
Let's cover the ITTOs.
So 121 in your Pembuck, page 121.
Okay, so here we will finalize all the
activities for the project.
Make sure all of the work has been done.
We will do lessons learned and then we'll
release the team.
Now if it is a phase you close the phase
this will be called an exit point or kill
gate exit gate or kill point and this is
where the organization the stakeholders
will decide whether or not to keep moving
forward so construction projects often
have the design phase that's what they
start with so here we should have designs
done and then our customer key
stakeholders sponsor, of course,
will have to accept the
entire designs or decide,
again, whether or not
they want to move forward.
So if they do, you'll go ahead and close
the phase, then you'll go through
initiating, planning, executing,
controlling, and closing again.
But let's concentrate here on closing the
entire project.
So what comes in?
we have a lot of ITTOs so the project
charter comes in had our high-level
project objectives in the first place
probably exit criteria as well our project
management plan of course tells us how
we're going to close the project and we'll
include our baselines again here we the p
.m.
and team are ensuring that all
the work has been completed
and before i forget even if
a project is terminated early.
You still close.
All right.
Our project documents, everything we've
created, really important here will be the
requirements documentation, making sure
everything was done.
That is what was used to create those
baselines in the first place.
Big, big, big here will be accepted
deliverables.
So we will cover these in
different processes, but direct
and manage a project work
process creates the deliverables.
So remember, we're in executing,
and we're up at the top in integration.
Well, do we just hand over those
deliverables?
Nope.
We check them first in control quality.
So let's say a baby car seat is being
upgraded for the new regulations.
so we will appraise check the baby car
seat on the way along the way and when we
are done all of that is in control quality
all right so what we want will be verified
deliverables we've checked them the
deliverables for correctness conformance
completeness if they're good yep we've
verified those deliverables then the
verified deliverables feed into validate
scope process.
So it's invalidate scope where a sponsor
customer or with the house Reno,
the homeowners are walking through
inspecting.
So that's where we will get accepted
deliverables.
And in the IT world, that's called user
acceptance testing at the end of a review
demo they are customer sponsor product
owner with agile will we will do that demo
this is the time to review do the user
acceptance testing and hopefully we will
have accepted deliverables otherwise we'll
have to go back and fix things which will
require a change request so that'll be
covered in a process coming up so i had to
let you know how we we got to accepted
deliverables.
So this is the reason you need to cover
all of these integration processes again.
I'm covering at the main level,
everything the PM we do to manage,
coordinate, unify this
project, especially this is,
you know, focused on
traditional predictive projects.
All right.
So you're going to want to review these
because a lot of this we haven't covered
yet as you go through scope, schedule,
quality, and whatnot, you will end up
seeing all these processes
where we create all these plans
and documents and baselines
and why they are coming in here.
All right.
Your business case, the business
documents, which include the business case
and benefits management
plans, were inputs to
develop project charter
process in the first place.
In the very beginning, there was a reason,
a need for the project in that business
case, along with the feasibility and
justification of the project.
It goes hand-in-hand with the benefits
management plan.
How is the project going to benefit the
organization?
Usually make money, save money,
promote goodwill, for example.
And then those agreements,
contracts, which came in to
develop project charter
process in the first place too.
legal binding documents we have to make
sure everything was done and you will see
if we end up hiring sellers vendors
contractors we will have agreements with
each of them so we again enclosing the
entire project have to make sure that
everything all the work had been completed
before we get here we're ensuring
everything is done in close the project So
the contracts, if we get vendors,
we'll go hand in hand with our procurement
documentation, like request for proposal,
invitation to bid, quote.
And then our OPAs will come in.
We'll follow the policies, processes,
procedures to close.
We will use expert judgment, our brains,
ours, our team member, Smease.
We will do data analysis.
We'll look at all the documentation,
make sure everything was completed.
You can also go back in time, do
regression analysis.
Trend analysis is we're documenting how we
performed over time, better or worse.
And then variance analysis, how far off
are we from our plan?
That will be especially important if your
project is terminated early.
How far off are we from our original
objectives?
And then, of course, we're having a
meeting to close the entire project.
project.
But part of that will be lessons learned.
So before we officially
release the team here, anybody
who's still part of the project,
we will do lessons learn.
All right.
So that's a big part of the meeting here.
Your outputs will update project
documents.
We'll update the lessons learned register
for the last time.
This is where we will hand over,
transition everything.
All our deliverables.
Those are product, services, processes,
results.
your deliverables will be transitioned
handed over to production or operations to
actually use we will send out a final
report letting our stakeholders know we
are completing the project work and well
that it's all done and we will update our
OPAs we've been
pulling from them all along
we contribute to them
organizational learning